outervision.com 2019-03-02

# eXtreme Outer Vision Privacy Policy

**Last Revised: April 25, 2018**

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. 

* * *

**What personal information do we collect?**

eXtreme Outer Vision cares about your privacy.  For this reason, we collect and use personal data only as it might be needed for us to deliver to you our world-class services and websites (collectively, our “Services”). Your personal data includes information such as:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Other data collected that could directly or indirectly identify you.

Our Privacy Policy is intended to describe to you how and what data we collect, and how and why we use your personal data. It also describes options we provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal data that we process. 

If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach us by completing the following contact form. The inbox associated with this contact form is actively monitored and managed, so that we can deliver an experience that you can confidently trust. 

We collect information so that we can provide the best possible experience when you utilize our Services.  Much of what you likely consider personal data is collected directly from you when you: 

(1)    request assistance from our customer support team (ex: email); 

(2)    complete contact forms or request product updates or request newsletters or other information from us (ex: email); or

(3)    participate in contests and surveys, or otherwise participate in activities we promote that might require information about you.  

However, we also collect additional information when delivering our Services to you to ensure necessary and optimal performance.  These methods of collection may not be as obvious to you, so we wanted to highlight and explain below a bit more about what these might be (as they vary from time to time) and how they work:

**Cookies**   **and similar technologies**  on our websites and our mobile applications allow us to track your browsing behavior, links clicked, items purchased, your device type, and to collect various data, including analytics, about how you use and interact with our Services. This allows us to provide you with more relevant product offerings, a better experience on our sites and mobile applications, and to collect, analyze and improve the performance of our Services. We may also collect your location (IP address) so that we can personalize our Services. For additional information, and to learn how to manage the technologies we utilize, please visit our Cookie Policy.   

**Data about Usage of Services**  is automatically collected when you use and interact with our Services, including metadata, log files, cookie/device IDs and location information. This information includes specific data about your interactions with the features, content and links (including those of third-parties, such as social media plugins) contained within the Services, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and settings, the date and time the Services were used, information about browser configuration and plugins, language preferences and cookie data, information about devices accessing the Services, including type of device, what operating system is used, device settings, application IDs, unique device identifiers and error data, and some of this data collected might be capable of and be used to approximate your location. 

**Supplemented Data  **We do not collect or use Supplemented Data for storing information to target advertising to you on or off our sites.

**How do we use your information?**

We strongly believe in both minimizing the data we collect and limiting its use and purpose to only that (1)  _for which we have been given permission_ , (2)  _as necessary to deliver the Services you interact with_ , or (3)  _as we might be required or permitted for legal compliance or other lawful purposes_. These uses include:

**Delivering, improving, updating and enhancing the Services we provide to you.   **We collect various information relating to your use and/or interactions with our Services. We utilize this information to:

  * Improve and optimize the operation and performance of our Services (again, including our websites and mobile applications)
  * Diagnose problems with and identify any security risks, errors, or needed enhancements to the Services
  * Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our Services and systems
  * Collecting aggregate statistics about use of the Services
  * Understand and analyze how you use our Services and what products and services are most relevant to you.

Often, much of the data collected is aggregated or statistical data about how individuals use our Services, and is not linked to any personal data, but to the extent it is itself personal data, or is linked or linkable to personal data, we treat it accordingly. 

**Third-party disclousure.  **With your consent only, we may share your personal information such as _Name, Address, Email, Telephone Number_ with our trusted partners in order to supply you with prizes via our contests or giveaways in which you have willingly participated in. Otherwise, we do not sell, trade, or transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

**Communicating with you.  **We may contact you directly regarding products or services you have signed up from us, such as necessary to deliver service related communications. ** ** We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. These contacts may include:

  * Email
  * Text (SMS) messages

If you wish to unsubscribe from our Service update or Product availability emails, you may do so by submitting us a request via the following contact form. Your email address will be unsubscribed within 72 hours of request.

If you believe that anyone has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us by completing the following contact form.

**Transfer of personal data abroad**.  If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from our US location that may be outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

**Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests**. We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (such as subpoena requests), to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process. We will also share your information to the extent necessary to comply with ICANN or any ccTLD rules, regulations and policies when you register a domain name with us.

**Website analytics**.  We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Google Analytics and AddThis to collect information about how you interact with our website or mobile applications, including what pages you visit, what site you visited prior to visiting our website, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use and network and IP information. We use the information provided by these tools to improve our Services. These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider (ex: Google for Google Analytics). The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside. Though information collected does not include personal data such as name, address, telephone number, email address, etc., the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our Cookie Policy or by utilizing settings in your browser or third-party tools, such as [Disconnect](https://disconnect.me/disconnect), [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/) and others.

**Targeted advertisements.  **Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own.  These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on our webpages and other websites.  Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness.  If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**Third-party websites**.  Our website and our mobile applications contain links to third-party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third-party sites.  Please read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**The E.U-U.S and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks.**

**How you can access, update or delete your data.**

Since our Services do not require user registration or account creation the only personal information that we store is your Email Address, which you used to subscribe to our Service or Product updates.

To view, update, delete or port your personal data (where available), or to unsubscribe from our Service updates or Product availability emails, please submit us a request via the following contact form.

**How we secure, store and retain your data.**

We follow generally accepted standards to store and protect the personal data we collect, both during transmission and once received and stored, including utilization of encryption where appropriate.

We retain personal data only for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested and thereafter for a variety of legitimate legal or business purposes. These might include retention periods:

  * mandated by law, contract or similar obligations applicable to our business operations;
  * for preserving, resolving, defending or enforcing our legal/contractual rights; or
  * needed to maintain adequate and accurate business and financial records.

If you have any questions about the security or retention of your personal data, you may reach us by completing the following contact form.

_**‘Do Not Track’**_ **  notifications.**

Some browsers allow you to automatically notify websites you visit not to track you using a “Do Not Track” signal. There is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Like many websites and online services, we currently do not alter our practices when we receive a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you may wish to visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

**Changes in our Privacy Policy.**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy and any other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page, at least thirty (30) days prior to the implementation of the changes.

**Contact us.**

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy, our practices or our Services, you may reach us by completing the following contact form.

**_We will respond to all requests, inquiries or concerns within thirty (30) days._**
